{"questions":
  [
    {
      "question": "What was used as the primary source of protection for the soldiers on the front lines?",
      "hint": "What ran along the western front?",
      "answers": ["Trenches", "Tanks", "Field Telephone", "Machine Gun"],
      "explanation": "Trenches were a huge part of WWI, given that most of WWI was spent in a trench!"
    },
    {
      "question": "What weapon was used to provide protection as well as mobile firepower?",
      "hint": "Was used to break stalemates",
      "answers": ["Tanks", "Aircraft", "Artillery", "Battleship"],
      "explanation": "Tanks were used to break stalemates later on in the war and provided mobile firepower along with protection. TL;DR: Tanks were basically big cars with a gun on the front."
    },
    {
      "question": "What emerging technology was used to bomb the enemy from above?",
      "hint": "Above means in the air.",
      "answers": ["Aircraft", "Artillery", "Mustard Gas", "Flamethrower"],
      "explanation": "In World War I, aircraft were first used to bomb the enemy from above, and were later used in \"dogfights\"."
    },
    {
      "question": "What technology aided in fast communication?",
      "hint": "The precursor to something that almost everyone has nowadays.",
      "answers": ["Field Telephone", "Tanks", "Machine Guns", "Aircraft"],
      "explanation": "Telephone makes fast communication. Simple as that."
    },
    {
      "question": "What technology did the Germans first use that needed 2+ men to operate?",
      "hint": "This weapon went brrrrr.",
      "answers": ["Machine Gun", "Tanks", "Flamethrower", "Submarine"],
      "explanation": "The Germans first used the machine gun. It needed 2+ people to operate, one to aim and fire, the other to feed the gun bullets."
    },
    {
      "question": "What very controversial weapon was used by both sides, although more often used by the Germans?",
      "hint": "Something that needed gas masks.",
      "answers": ["Mustard Gas", "Flamethrower", "Field Telephone", "Trench"],
      "explanation": "Mustard gas was a controversial weapon even during WWI, and the troops that were attacked with it needed gas masks to survive. It was usually noticed when it was too late."
    },
    {
      "question": "What weapon could kill in an instant and caused most WWI deaths?",
      "hint": "This looked like a huge canon.",
      "answers": ["Artillery", "Submarine", "Mustard Gas", "Flamethrower"],
      "explanation": "Artillery caused 60% of all WWI deaths. It was a commonly used weapon against trenches because the weapon could kill from above."
    },
    {
      "question": "What weapon was used by the Germans to rival the British Navy?",
      "hint": "Glub glub",
      "answers": ["Submarine", "Battleship", "Flamethrower", "Tanks"],
      "explanation": "Submarines/u-boats were used by the Germans to sink civillian ships (like the Lusitania). It was developed to rival the British Navy."
    },
    {
      "question": "What massive weapon was used in Navies?",
      "hint": "Seen as the \"King of the Seas\" during WWI.",
      "answers": ["Battleships", "Submarines", "Artillery", "Trenches"],
      "explanation": "Battleships were huge, defended ships used in battle in the seas."
    },
    {
      "question": "What weapon looked super cool and was used to clear out trenches? This weapon also had a short range.",
      "hint": "Was very hot.",
      "answers": ["Flamethrower", "Artillery", "Machine Gun", "Field Telephone"],
      "explanation": "Flamethrowers had a short range (around 20 feet) and were used to clear out trenches because, fun fact, people don't like fire. When not used to kill people, flamethrowers look pretty cool."
    }
  ]
}
